Dom Alexander (Dom, he/him)

Denver, CO | 210-837-0670 | dom.alexan@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn | Github | Blog</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Motivated, disciplined, and armed with ruthless persistence, I am a software developer cutting my teeth on tech as it sprints forward towards an ever-expanding horizon. Experienced with full-stack development using languages such as HTML, CSS, JS, TS, React, Ruby on Rails, and Python. In the spirit of always pursuing knowledge, I am currently learning C# and MongoDB. A performance-driven problem solver, I am dedicated to helping your team realise its goals in the most elegant and functional ways possible.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding Languages & Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JS, TS, MERN, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL,

Python

Currently learning: C#, MongoDB

Other Technologies: VS Code, Git, GitHub, Postman, Wordpress, Microsoft Office (all suites), Adobe

Creative Suite (Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Dreamweaver)

Other Skills: Copywriting, Editing, ESL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

KP2020JOBS - Github | Private Production

A utility that runs via task scheduler at regular intervals to export orders and import various files from Kaiser Permanente.

- → Utilising C# in order to build a clean, consistent app according to client needs Currently:
 - Removing dependency on JI.AppLogging (replace with NLog or Serilog?)
 - Removing dependency on JobsFramework (pull into main project)
 - General refactoring to implement best practices
 - Upgrading to .NET6

Cropsey - Github | Demo

• A simple responsive app (React + Rails) to showcase the NY-based band Cropsey

The Black Market - Github | Currently in Development

A full-stack (React + Rails) app dedicated to user-to-user sales & purchasing of alternative vinyls/records.

- Implemented back end state management + auditing via the gems aasm & auditor to create a more manageable db
- Utilised create-react-app to initially build the client before then updating to Next.js
- Implemented basic user authentication via sessions && cookies

EXPERIENCE

Coding For Hermit Crabs

Software Engineer Apprentice

Denver, Colorado (Remote) 03/2023 - Present

- Developing an ever-expanding base curriculum of HTML, CSS, and JS + React for novice students beginning to learn to program
- Collaborating with other interns on projects intended to showcase the capabilities of basic apps written in HTML, CSS, and React

Bacon Social House LLC

Bartender

Denver, Colorado 04/2021 - 07/2022

 Collaborated with all front of house staff to provide excellent service to guests while averaging a \$25+ PPA

- Managed bar prep, inventory, and cash drawers
- Conducted proficient sales transactions using Aloha & Toast POS

<u>Freelance</u> Editor & English Teacher

Adelaide, SA | Denver, CO 01/2018 - 07/2022

- Negotiated individual learning goals to be able to guide students towards a productive, personalised, and realised outcome
- Crafted curriculum for classes of 20-30 students with ages ranging from young adult (12+), adult (18+), and seniors (60+)
- Initiated study groups for students who intended to take the IELTS, resulting in band scores of an average of 7.5-9 per student

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Denver, Colorado
10/ 2022 - 02/2023

University of Colorado - DenverDenver, ColoradoBachelors of Arts - English (Literature) (Pending)08/2020 - 10/2022

Northwest Vista College San Antonio, Texas Associates of Arts - English 06/2015 - 12/2017

University of Adelaide, Cambridge University

Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages

Adelaide, South Australia 01/2018